{
    "id": "fe0c331fd65c4fcba42cf0116f4af5cd",
    "title": "Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "This is Samuel ……………………. works with me.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun who has one form when it is used as the subject and another form when it is used as the object. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This is Samuel with ……………………… I am working at the moment.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun who becomes whom when it is used as the object.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "John and …………………….. are going skiing this weekend.",
            "description": "When a pronoun acts as the subject of the verb it should be in its subject form.",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "me",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Between you and ……………………, I think there is trouble in their paradise.",
            "description": "Here the pronoun me is the object of the preposition between. ",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "me",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "With ……………………….. did you go?",
            "description": "We must use whom after a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "There is the guy ……………………….. we met at the club yesterday.",
            "description": "Whom is unusual in identifying relative clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "This is James, ……………………….. we met at the club yesterday.",
            "description": "Whom is common in non-identifying relative clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have a number of English friends and most of …………………….. live in London.",
            "description": "We do not use a relative pronoun in a coordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "whom",
                "them",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She has a number of American relatives, most of ………………….. live in Chicago.",
            "description": "In a relative clause we use who or whom to refer back to a noun in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "them",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the doctor …………………….. lives next door.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun acts as the subject or object of the verb in the relative clause. Hence we do not need another noun. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "who he",
                "he"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… leaves last should put the lights out.",
            "description": "Whoever means the same as ‘the person who’.",
            "answers": [
                "Who",
                "Whoever",
                "He/She"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is I ………………………. need your help.",
            "description": "If we use a subject pronoun after ‘it is’, the subject of the relative clause should be who. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}